COMMON WEALTH
I heard you.
You have a job in a disco.
Doing what, the accounting?
The door?
As a bouncer? Are you nuts?
You could get killed!
Tell me about it later.
Don't get angry.
You just never stop calling me.
I'm sorry. Yes.
Yes, I love you a lot.
I'm nervous about the flat.
I haven't sold a single one.
Yes, it started well,
but after that...
Also, some clients have been
waiting for me
for a half hour
in this freezing weather.
It's pouring and I'm dressed up.
You're lucky.
You can wear
a jogging suit to work.
What? A tuxedo?
You had to rent one?
Are you crazy or what?
They have to pay for that.
You think firemen
buy their helmets?
We'll talk about it later.
Okay, honey.
I love you a lot!
Yes, bye.
He's such a pain!
Luis?
Julia, from the agency.
Excuse me, I was
talking to a client
who's interested in this flat.
Did I say it was amazing?
- Yes, you did.
- On the phone.
Well, well, well.
Here are the super-advantages.
One, near the subway.
Two, downtown.
Three, there are schools
for the kids,
and four, parks
where they can play.
- We don't have kids.
- You don't? Good.
Me neither. It leaves you free to go
to the movies or to a bingo parlor.
I don't play bingo,
it was just an example.
You can walk
anywhere from here.
- So there's no garage?
- No.
There's no... garage.
Let's see.
This is it. By the way,
I wanted to warn you
that these old flats usually
have old furniture
and that funny
seventies wallpaper...
I can imagine it. Let's go.
That's what I mean, you have
to use your imagination.
They usualy belong
to elderly people.
Sometimes they smell bad...
But not in this case.
Look at that.
This is your typical
amazing flat, period.
It's what we call
"ready to live in".
And it's completely furnished.
It has pictures, lamps,
a TV, a radio,
a sofa...
I think it's a sofa bed.
No, it's a sofa sofa,
and a good one.
This looks like leather.
High-quality! Not like mine,
which is like a beach chair.
Every time I show
someone this flat,
I want it for myself.
Though to each his own
and I won't pressure you.
- The owner lives here?
- The owner?
What owner? I don't think so.
No, it says it's free.
You can sign for it and
come live here tomorrow.
What do you think?
Can we see the other rooms?
Of course, no problem.
Let's see the bedroom.
But first, the closet.
Lots of room.
The bedroom, I think...
What a beautiful bed!
It must be king size.
A waterbed, like in Las Vegas!
What's the price?
Not that I've ever
been in Las Vegas.
But this is nice.
And if you get seasick,
you can turn it off.
I imagine. There must be
a button somewhere.
And the price?
Didn't they tell you?
Think about it, anyway.
I'll give you my card...
Not too much...
Her, it was her...
You're like
a ventriloquist's dummy!
Go ahead, laugh.
What a day I've had!
I get a cab at the disco,
and guess who I meet?
- Who?
- Antonio Pesadas.
Pesadas who worked with me
at the insurance company.
Right. He was unbearable.
Well, he still is.
But now he's a taxi driver.
- He got laid off, too.
- Just like you.
I didn't get fired for doing
something wrong. It was downsizing.
Right. He was
superfluous, too.
I don't know what he was.
But if you mean
I'm "superfluous"...
Please. It was four years ago.
Forget it.
But you keep reminding me.
You're saying I lost my job
because I was superfluous.
Listen: maybe Pesadas
was superfluous,
but I wasn't, I was essential.
What's all this?
It's a romantic dinner.
But... whose flat is this?
Nobody's. But since I'm
the only one with a key...
Let's see if I get it.
This is one of the agency flats,
and you're cooking in it?
Don't start acting
like you were my father.
I'm not. But you do whatever you
want without checking with me!
Acting like your father...
Ricardo, we'll clean up afterwards
and they won't find out.
- They will and they'll fire you.
- So what?
Let them. It's only
a 15-day temp job.
And it's worth it.
It has a Jacuzzi.
A what?
A hot tub, Ricardo.
And a sauna,
a Finnish sauna.
You sure it's Finnish?
And the best part is...
Come on.
- It moves!
- It's a waterbed.
You can change the temperature.
What if you want it to stop?
There must be
a button somewhere.
Wait, wait...
Stop!
Julia, you know I need
to be relaxed for this.
We've waited
six months for you to relax!
That long?
Try to understand.
Someone could
come in any time.
We're alone.
You'll relax, leave it to me.
- What's that noise?
- The pipes.
It's the neighbor's TV.
You can hear it perfectly.
The walls are thin.
Forget about it
and concentrate.
If we can hear them,
they can hear us.
Stop being paranoid.
Let them hear us.
They'll get off on it.
Get it off of me!
What now?
That's disgusting!
Where did they come from?
I told you we shouldn't be here.
Don't start with your Jesuit school
guilt complex, Ricardo!
But we are guilty.
Okay, we're guilty.
We're fornicating
like degenerate beasts,
but the cockroaches
don't know that!
You're driving me crazy!
You're right, sorry.
But they really give me
the creeps.
Me too, believe me.
We'll close the door,
go into the living room...
...Clean up and go home.
Please, Julia.
No.
We'll stay here.
Why?
Because I say so.
Our house is freezing,
and this is a special night.
Yeah, Walpurgis night.
- Julia...
- You don't feel like it.
- You don't mind, do you?
- No, not at all.
We're like Krishnas.
Tomorrow we'll beg in the park.
That would be better.
In the disco,
this 12-year-old
with baggy pants
said he'd kill me
because I asked for his ID.
Who would ever hire you
as a bouncer?
I told the temp agency
I would do anything.
Should I turn on the TV?
The neighbor's isn't enough?
What a great romantic dinner.
The vulture,
nature's gravedigger,
devours the dead.
When one vulture
finds a carcass,
twenty more appear
to share it.
A voracious jackal joins them.
The somber party continues
until nothing's left.
Hello?
God! Richard!
Richard, wake up!
God, the 9:00 people!
Just a little more...
Now you feel affectionate?
Men!
We have time for a quickie.
To dress quickly.
- What's that?
- The doorbell.
- Who is it?
- A client, damnit!
I have to explain everything.
- Great. Always in a hurry.
- Carlos Manzanares?
Julia García.
I was expecting you.
First, the location.
Here are the super-advantages.
One, near the subway.
Two,
downtown. Three, schools
for the kids, and four,
parks where they can play.
Fantastic.
High-quality leather.
A sofa to last a lifetime.
- What's this?
- Look.
- Stains just wipe off.
- Right.
Let me show you
the bedroom.
No, let me show you
the kitchen.
Fully equipped,
it even has a toaster.
I said you should see
the kitchen.
- What is this?
- A dampness problem.
- Who are you calling?
- The fire department.
There's no need to.
We can fix this.
A stitch in time...
The man upstairs must
have left a faucet on.
If the agency finds out...
Stop, it's here!
Come on, quickly!
- What's going on?
- Today is the day, Encarna.
- The old man? No!
- Yes. Something bad has happened.
I've prayed for this moment!
I hope it's not a false alarm.
God forbid.
They must have
left a faucet on.
- Let's see...
- This is my flat!
No, excuse me.
That's the door.
Let's see. Please.
Get back, we need room.
Ma'am, please!
Have you nothing to do?
What's up?
Don't come out
dressed like a drag queen!
Ring first.
Mind your own business.
Yes, you should ring.
What the fuck did you call us for?
To ring the bell?
- I didn't call you.
- Ignore her.
- What if he's asleep?
- Asleep? Bullshit!
Besides, he never opens
the door, even if you ring.
He's a dangerous lunatic.
He'll leave the gas on someday
and blow us up.
- Hit it!
- Ma'am!
Don't touch my ax,
damnit!
It must be bolted.
- With a iron bar.
- And chains.
They haven't gone in yet?
They're trying.
Tell María and Salas.
This isn't a circus.
Who the hell is the manager?
He's not here. He took
his kids to Disneyland.
In Paris,
not the "Walt Disney's" one.
It had to happen today.
Bad luck.
- Aren't you the manager?
- No, no.
Who's she?
Who are you?
We don't know her.
She bought the engineer's flat.
Well, "bought"...
Julián Chueca,
from the videoclub.
Nice to meet you.
We met your husband
downstairs at the door.
He's very elegant.
- He's a croupier in a casino.
- Really?
He said he was going
to a disco.
Well, it's a disco-casino.
What do you think?
The Rotaflex.
Okay, everyone downstairs.
I'm surfing the net...
Everyone downstairs.
My son's right. Why can't we
stay if we live here?
Because I say so, okay?
- No need to get cocky.
- Downstairs!
- It's our home!
- She's staying!
What a stench!
What is all this fucking shit?
Disgusting!
- Where did you come from?
- My flat. The door was open.
Stay out of our way.
This is no joke.
There's the leak.
It must be a broken pipe.
How could someone
live like this?
I didn't know him.
You hear that?
Here's our friend,
watching TV.
God!
- What are you doing here?
- He's dead!
Of course he's dead.
We see this every month.
He died weeks ago.
He was alone, with no family
to look after him.
- What's that smell?
- That smell...
is the smell of rotting flesh.
The cat has probably been
feeding on the body,
and I can assure you,
it's not a pretty sight.
Paco!
Cut the bullshit.
Hey?
Are you there?
What are you doing?
What are you looking for?
Fifteen men
on a dead man's chest.
Ho, ho, ho, and a bottle
of rum.
Up. What are you doing?
Fuck,we'll have to bend him.
Bend him?
Just raise him a bit.
There we go.
He was snobbish and thin.
- Hold on, ma'am, he's falling!
- Over here.
Have a toke, Juanillo.
Always so proud,
and look at him now.
God fucking damn it!
Calm down.
Come on!
Slow down, Toni!
This guy stinks!
- Finally! That bastard.
- You sure he's dead?
That's enough already!
Ladies!
There's no need to push us.
Is that her?
The one in the suit.
How did she get in?
She called the fire department.
The bitch!
A crossword puzzle?
Hello?
Hi, dear.
No, I'm in a café.
Yes, the firemen came.
It was a pipe or something.
Did you tell people it was our
flat? They think we live here,
I mean, there.
No, if they see we're not there,
the agency might find out.
So I should spend
the night.
Are you going home?
Okay, I'll see you tomorrow.
Careful with the kid
in baggy pants. Bye.
The secret is Mr. Clean.
It's a cinch!
Great!
You scrubbed
everything but my back.
Mr. Clean does
the hard work for you.
The secret is Mr. Clean.
If Ricardo knew, he'd kill me.
Fifteen men
on a dead man's chest.
Ho, ho, ho,
and a bottle of rum.
It's loose!
What's going on?
I must talk to that woman.
With a knife? You're crazy, Castro.
Give it to me.
You'll ruin everything!
What is it? Is it her?
Shut up! I can't hear.
Let me see!
Get back, Castro.
Just settle down.
- Well?
- Excuse me?
Taking out the trash?
Yes. There's a lot
when you're moving in.
Wait a second.
Stay right there.
Don't worry.
- I'll take it down.
- No, no.
- I'll go with you.
- I don't mind.
But I do.
- How's your husband?
- He's exhausted.
- You know what moving's like.
- No, I don't.
I was born and will die
in this building.
I didn't see you bring
too many things.
The flat was ready
to live in.
- Did you know the engineer?
- Who?
The previous owner.
No, I got it
through an agency.
I'd never use an agency!
- Why not?
- They're all thieves.
They take your money
without doing anything.
- Shall we go up?
- No.
I have to buy some cigarettes.
Cigarettes...
- No, no! Wait!
- What?
It's just paper.
Hold on!
My husband's into recycling.
Recycling, recycling...
That's two hundred bills worth
5,000 pesetas
in each bunch
and there are 300 bunches,
that makes...
300 million pesetas.
Calm.
I'm a mature woman.
This is just something
that happened.
I have to accept it as normal.
I won't lose controI.
No.
I'm a multimillionaire,
that's all.
I'm totally rich.
Without spending a penny,
I could live off the interest
and never work again.
I could go around the world
as many times as I can take.
Is this going to affect me?
No.
I'm the same as always.
A millionaire, but the same.
Why are you here?
- You don't want to see me?
- No!
I mean, yes, but weren't you
going home?
Fine, I'll go.
- Don't be silly. What happened?
- The disco is history.
- They fired you?
- No, I quit!
Why do you always say that?
Did the 12-year-old
do that to you?
Don't. No, worse.
The disco owner,
obeying the kid's father.
I lasted two days.
I'm the king of disco bouncers.
I'm King Kong!
The giant shithead bouncer.
You want a beer?
We have beer here now?
What?
Have we moved in completely?
I have something
important to tell you.
Not tonight. Tell me
the bad news tomorrow.
It's not bad news,
on the contrary.
Imagine something
changing everything.
Everything,
I mean, everything.
A stroke of luck.
Julia, look who
you're talking to here.
I have nothing.
I've been beaten
and humiliated,
I feel ridiculous.
I prefer not
to imagine anything.
Fine.
If you don't want to know...
THE STRONGEST DRUG
ISN'T SPEED
IT'S MONEY
Which is better?
A Rover or a Mercedes?
I'd prefer a Mercedes.
They're classy, elegant.
Yeah, fucking great.
I want to be reincarnated
as a fucker who owns one.
In this life, we'll never
put our asses in one of those.
Unless we catch Pesadas' taxi.
The cocksucker has a Mercedes.
Your character is turning bitter.
You always say
I have no character.
What you didn't have was bitterness.
Now I'm embittered.
That's what you're calling me!
What about you? Always
looking over my shoulder.
- What?
- Don't pretend to be offended.
Always saying people
can't put up with me.
"What, fired again?"
What are you saying?
You heard me.
Look. Just because
things aren't going well
doesn't give you
the right to be rude.
For years, "Mr. Rude"
has kept our thing afloat.
You know that?
- What thing?
- Our thing.
Our relationship, the bills,
the rent, everything!
Look,
let's talk about this tomorrow.
We used to live off
my salary, but now
you have to work, too,
and never stop
rubbing my face in it
so that I know you're in charge
now. Think I don't get it?
A nice romantic dinner...
Well, my life is going to hell
and I can't buy
an Audi or a Mercedes.
I can't! Okay?
I had good news,
but now I don't even
feel like telling you!
And I don't feel
like staying here!
- Where are you going?
- Home.
I don't want to stay in this flat
because it's what we'll never have!
You don't realize that.
I'll never have
this flat or that car
or a girI like
the one in the ad!
So you have to settle for
someone like me.
I didn't say that.
Yes, you did, and you meant it.
Well, I have to settle for you
and you for me. So what?
At least I recognize my limitations
and don't expect strokes of luck.
Ricardo!
What?
You're making a huge mistake.
Quique, the lady
needs something.
Everything okay?
The best breakfast
in Madrid, Quique.
Is there a newspaper here?
If there isn't, there will be.
Excuse me...
Napoleon was exiled to Elba,
the Canary Islands,
or Treasure Island?
What?
The Trivia machine.
Well, it must be Elba.
Okay.
Thank you.
Picking up girls, Charli?
The horny little guy.
I was just asking her
about Napoleon.
His mother gets angry
with me because
he spends
the shopping money on that.
How dare you talk
like that about me!
Charli. Charli, Charli...
My mother has nothing
to do with this.
5th floor, right?
- You're the new neighbor.
- Hi, Charli. I'm Julia.
Nice to meet you.
If you need anything...
I've got to go to the butcher's.
I have number 35.
25 was 10 minutes ago.
That's 1,525 pesetas.
Cheap for Madrid.
- I don't think so.
- It's no good?
It is. With the E.U.,
everything's good.
The bank will change it.
But it's paid for.
Really? By whom?
Oswaldo,
the Cuban dance teacher.
He's really good.
He dances merengue, salsa,
the lambada, that kind of thing...
He's something else.
- Tell him thanks when you see him.
- Okay.
ELDERLY MAN DIES WATCHING TV
...CIFUENTES, 88,
WITH NO KNOWN RELATIVES...
What are you doing?
You're here.
I got it off. Silicon.
Some bastard is blocking
everybody's locks.
Well, you must be busy. I'm
on the 3rd floor if you need me.
And careful,
there's lots of thieves around!
Hello?
Hi, how are you?
I'm in the hospital
with my husband.
He had an accident.
He was beaten up in a disco.
Twenty guys with metaI bats.
Right, soccer hooligans.
I don't know. That's why
I didn't go to the office.
Show a flat? Now?
I don't think I can.
Which one?
Other buyers, right.
The "ready to live in" one?
When are they coming?
Now?
Yes, I'll be there
in five minutes.
No, don't send anyone,
I'll go.
It's not serious. His head
or his back or something,
I didn't really understand.
Okay.
Sorry, I'm losing the signaI.
Talk to you later.
Hi, Julia García.
Is this a bad time?
Not at all, come in.
Here are the super-advantages.
One, near the subway. But you
look more like taxi type people.
Two, downtown.
Near a bingo parlor. A shot of
anisette and a game or two. Great!
And three. Schools, blah,
blah, blah. Kids, etc.
But you have no kids.
What?
You're into doing "scissors".
- Excuse me?
- She thinks we sew?
"Scissors". It's on your card.
"Lesbian battle-axes
need flat to do scissors. "
- Please!
- What's "scissors"?
Well, think about it, then.
We'll keep in touch.
Shut up! Don't you get it?
Hello.
Excuse me. Are you going
on a trip?
I just don't stop.
I'm so busy.
Now I have to take these clothes
to my husband in the hospital.
What happened?
Nothing.
He was hit by a truck.
- I'm sorry.
- It was awful.
And the truck was full of
chemicals that disfigured his face.
That's terrible!
- I should go...
- No, don't.
It's not your fault.
I came to invite you
to a party.
- Really? When is it?
- Tonight.
Every year I celebrate
the day I came to Madrid.
I'm a little sentimentaI.
- I'd celebrate it too.
- Right.
I'll be there.
What about your husband?
He doesn't mind what I do.
Besides, I can't do much
at the hospitalTr
All those tubes.
Of course. You need...
to get away from it all.
- Exactly!
- Right.
So you will come tonight.
Around nine?
Great!
And thanks for the coffee!
She...
slips and runs into me...
I know the day I lose her
I'll suffer for her again,
and once again
I'll find her...
with another face,
another body...
We've spotted the target, sir.
We're waiting for instructions.
...let whatever God wills occur...
We'll take her
to the Dark Side.
It's time to take out
our light saber.
The Force...
I feel the Force!
It's coming! The Force!
The Force!
The Force, the Force...
Charli! Open the door,
you pig!
I know what you're doing!
The Force!
Yes, the Force!
Knock it off!
Lucía? Hi, it's Julia.
Remember me?
Right. It's been a long time.
I'm calling to
ask you something,
since you work in a bank...
You're going to laugh.
My friend inherited a lot of money
in cash from her parents...
They must have had it at home,
under the mattress.
Anyway,
she wants to take it
to the bank...
What? No, of course I'm not
mixed up in anything funny.
The amount? I don't know,
say... 300 million.
Under a mattress.
That's not so strange.
Whatever. Imagine
someone, Miss X, appears
in the bank with that money.
What would you do?
Right.
Without thinking twice.
Well, I'll let my friend know that.
Okay. Great to talk to you.
We'll have to get
together sometime. Bye.
She'd call the police.
Idiot!
It's her!
Everyone get ready!
- Hi.
- What a surprise!
Well, I wasn't going to come,
but in the end...
What a party!
- Someone here wants to meet you.
- Really?
Hello, Julia. I'm Emilio.
The manager. Nice to meet you.
How was Eurodisney?
Well, news gets around.
I've been here two days and I feel
like I already know everybody.
Great, it was like a dream.
A children's paradise.
Is your family here?
No, they stayed. It's not
their fault I'm the manager.
So I'm on my own.
Everyone here is
from the building, right?
It's a very close community.
We're all interested
in the common good.
We have an interest in...
the building.
We've always lived here.
Ramona was born here.
Right. I've known her
since I was a boy. Cheers.
You're sure
she hasn't gone out?
Not since the Cuban went up.
I can't stand this.
Emilio gets some ideas...
That's what I say,
but no one listens.
He's brainwashed them.
What would you do?
We've got her here.
What are we waiting for?
I could fix this in a second.
Without Emilio finding out?
No one's moving from here.
Cookie! This is our song!
Come on, Cookie!
What fucking song?
I don't have
a song.
Stop being a dipshit!
You can dance with the retard.
Don't take it so hard.
He's very passionate.
Passionate?
What do you mean by that?
Well, about what he does.
He doesn't leave
things undone.
He leaves a lot undone.
Every night
we just watch videos.
I don't want to know
about anyone's private life.
Since you seem to be
such good friends lately...
Well listen to you!
Go dance, you have no idea.
Go on!
You're so bossy!
Take off yourjacket,
it's hot.
I'm fine.
You just don't want the girls
to see how fat you are.
I know you ate
all the canapés!
It's a shame what happened.
Yes, that poor old man.
It was terrible.
We meant your husband.
Right, the accident.
It was awful.
Accident? Wasn't he beat up
by skinheads?
He was. But it was an accident
because they took him
for someone else.
Right.
Did you know the old man?
The dead one?
- We all know each other here.
- He was strange.
Always alone.
- He never went out.
- The lottery win went to his head.
He won the lottery?
The sports lottery.
But that was a long time ago.
He was too afraid to go out.
Isn't that silly?
Afraid of us!
Afraid!
- Can I go now?
- No.
Emilio said
we all have to stay.
You made me sign it.
Do you want to end up
like the engineer?
And stop drinking.
How is it going?
I don't know.
The bitch is smart.
But she has the money.
We don't know that yet.
Ramona saw her with bags.
She sees what she wants to.
Why don't we go up
and search her place now?
You want to go up?
Stay calm.
We have to do this right.
We should have done it
right from the start.
Eurodisney!
Eurodisney
fucked us over completely!
I finally have
a vacation and... Shit!
You were brave, going into
that flat with the firemen.
What was it like? A cave?
More or less, yes.
What was the first thing
you saw?
Cockroaches, bags full
of garbage, and filth.
Nothing llse?
I know we sound morbid,
insisting like this.
We've just wondered
about it so long.
You can ask him, too.
He went in with me.
Domínguez! That's news.
The fucker went in
and didn't tell anyone.
I hope they weren't
boring you.
No, they're charming.
Everyone is, really.
They're like
a family to me.
I'm lucky to live here.
There aren't many
young people... like us.
It's my senior citizens party.
But they love to dance.
You just have to
start them off. Shall we?
No, I only dance at weddings.
- Come on, I'll teach you.
- Only at weddings!
Come on!
You don't have
to accompany me.
- You Cubans!
- We like taking care of women.
- I bet you say that to all of them.
- And it works!
How embarrassing!
We left together.
But possibly
each to their own flat.
No, you were already
in your own flat.
You didn't have to go.
You're right! I'm blasted!
They're thinking the worst.
Well, we can't
disappoint them.
Right, if they're going to gossip,
it might as well be true.
Wait... What about
your husband?
My husband.
What a pain, my husband.
I didn't want to say so, but
the hospital called. He's dead.
- Really?
- You heard me.
The anesthesia gave him
a heart attack.
But I don't want to think
about that now, I need to...
- To get away from it all.
- Right!
To get away from it all.
Isn't it amazing?
It can make waves.
The engineer had class.
- Did you know him?
- No.
But I've heard
a lot about him.
And the ceiling?
The finger of God
punished me the other day.
You know what?
He'll have reasons to.
We'll savagelly profane
this hoy waterbed.
Wait, wait a second.
I have ice cream.
I love ice cream.
But hurry back.
You forgot the ice cream.
- Were they listening?
- No.
They're beating up Domínguez.
It must be Castro.
Always the same.
Some people shouldn't drink.
What was that?
What, darling?
There's someone
in the living room.
Julia.
Julia, come back!
What is this?
What are you doing?
How did you get in?
Get out of my flat!
Your flat?
- Let's go.
- I'll call the police.
- Are you sure?
- Put that down.
What do you mean?
I don't think you would.
Forget it, Ramona.
- She doesn't fool me.
- Slut.
I'm sorry.
Let go, it's not yours!
I'll buy you one.
Well, let's leave.
Come on, let's go. Let's go.
Unbelievable!
Theyjust walked in!
Did you...?
Out of my home!
Get out right now!
You were all working together,
all of you!
You came up
to unlock the door.
God, how could I be so stupid?
To think you and I...
Get out! Get out!
Get out!
You'd better be
as innocent as you seem.
Get out!
Where do you think
you're going?
- What happened?
- Thanks to you, I was almost killed.
- I had nothing to do with it.
- Lying bitch!
You told them I had the money.
What do you want?
They're downstairs.
They'll take the money and kill us.
- You're crazy.
- Crazy?
They're crazy.
Think about the engineer.
He wouldn't sign
and he disappeared.
- I don't understand.
- Listen, your life's at stake.
We used to watch
the old man day and night.
Every day for years!
How did you know he had
the money at home?
One day the bank people
came with two big bags.
The 500 million stayed there.
It's 300 million.
- I heard 500.
-300. I counted it.
It doesn't matter.
It used to be a dream
that helped us get by.
To share his money
when he died.
But now he's dead, the money's
here and they know it.
- Get out.
- First my suitcase.
The suitcase!
Fucking greed will send us to hell.
Help me!
- Help!
- The elevator's stuck again?
Ignore her! Help!
Go tell Emlio
the elevator's stuck.
Don't! Don't move!
We just want to help.
Go back inside.
God! Get me out of here!
Don't or I'll kill you!
You hear me, you bitch?
It's all your fault!
Sticking your nose
in our business!
- What's wrong, Mommy?
- Go to your fucking room!
It's crushing me!
God, it's crushing me!
I can't hold on!
I'll tell Emilio
it's taken care of.
Tell him
the suitcase is his
if he gets me out!
God!
My God, no!
- It was an accident!
- Come on, come on!
Come on!
Scream and I'll cut you open!
Inside!
We don't have
anything to do with this.
- It must be Emilio.
- The manager?
Yes, it was his idea.
The old man
didn't enjoy his money.
We just didn't want it to go
to the tax administration.
How noble!
She must be in the patio.
Shut up!
Emilio's an accountant,
he understands it.
He said that if we worked
together patiently,
we'd get it
without hurting anyone.
And you believed him?
Not everyone.
Some walked out
and the rest of us signed
an agreement. Equal shares.
It was serious, but we never
thought anyone would get hurt.
May lightning strike him
if I'm lying!
- No!
- Shut up!
We're going outside. Keep your
mouth shut. You come, too.
Come on, outside!
- Are you going to kill Mommy?
- I don't know.
She's here!
Tell my husband.
He's in the videoclub.
Pull yourself together.
Let Hortensia go!
Relax, we can talk it over.
There's enough money
for everyone in there.
Don't do anything rash.
Stay back or I'll kill her!
Julia, you're not a killer.
But you people are. Back!
I'm leaving here
and I don't care how.
You're scared. We're not responsible
for what happened to Domínguez.
The elevator's
had problems before.
It's true, Julia.
We called the repairman.
We haven't hurt anyone.
How can you think that?
We're normaI, like you.
Normal? You killed Domínguez
and you want to kill me!
She's right. What is this?
We should just slit
her fucking throat.
Castro, shut up!
Give me the suitcase.
Fuck you!
Give me the suitcase
and leave.
You screwed with the old man
until he died of fright.
I won't let you bastards
keep the money!
Someone call
my husband, please!
She'll kill her and keep the money!
We've waited so long for this?
Let me think, damnit!
About what? Either I leave,
or there will be a massacre
you'll never fucking forget.
We have to give her
the money! We have to!
I'll kill her!
Put that away!
Castro!
Get out of the way!
Who the fuck called
the police?
Thank God
you got here in time.
Stay calm.
I'm Gutiérrez, the manager.
Here is the body.
It was a horrific sight.
No, no.
Don't look.
Damn accident!
She's leaving,
the bitch is leaving.
How long have you
been the manager?
You're not leaving here!
You want me to scream?
Do it. And explain
the suitcase to the police.
Excuse me, Julia.
I told them you were the last
person to see Domínguez alive.
Yes, but it all happened
so quickly...
Let's go to the station.
- The station? Why?
- For your statement.
Sorry, I don't have time.
I have a plane to catch.
Of course, that explains
the suitcase.
It's a business trip.
I'll call you
in a couple of days.
Sorry, that's impossible.
You can go after
giving your statement.
Why don't we do it here?
Excuse me, but I know
about these things.
The first thing we do
is interview witnesses.
Come on, we have to
let these men do their work.
- Use my flat.
- No!
There's no need,
we can use mine. Let's go.
Thanks for your help, Emilio,
but we don't need you.
Right, upstairs.
Go on up.
That's all, then. Right?
You might be called later
if there's an investigation.
There's something else.
In this building...
Something strange
is happening.
- What happened?
- Yes.
The inevitable. You left your wife
alone and she was almost killed.
I was in the videoclub.
No, I went to look for him
and only the blonde was there.
I must have been having a coffee.
I don't know.
If you don't know...
We've all been here on guard.
- What do we do now?
- I don't know, give me time.
- What if she tells them?
- About what?
The elevator, the party...
No, she'd have to tell them
about the money.
She held on tight
to that suitcase.
No, it's not that. It's...
complicated.
Let's just say that they
have been looking
for something for years
and I found it
in a couple days.
"They"?
The neighbors.
They know I have it
and they want to kill me.
But what did you find?
Ma'am, what
did you find?
This flat.
I know it sounds silly,
but it's nice.
It's furnished, with a view.
I found it by chance.
They've worked for years
for what they have.
People can be very envious.
But the elevator...?
She has a nicer flat
so they want to kill her.
Absurd, isn't it?
Forgive me, I'm nervous.
Everything's ready?
Yes, perfect.
She's leaving.
Do something.
Maybe you'd like an aperitif.
How about... a beer?
- No, thanks. We have to go.
- Come on.
Encarna, can you
get some beers?
- Right away.
- And olives.
Let's have a nice cold beer.
We do appreciate it,
but we're on duty.
A couple of beers
never hurt anyone.
No, they're good for you.
They don't want anything!
Let's go.
- Damn her.
- Emilio, she's going.
Julia...
He's talking to you.
You left the door open.
What?
The door. You forgot
to close the door.
Come back up.
Close it for me.
See you later.
Julia, lock it if you're
going on a trip
to keep out the burglars.
Right, officers?
He's right,
you should lock it.
Well.
All right, but wait for me here.
- I'll be right back.
- Don't worry.
Hurry, you'll miss your plane.
The policeman downstairs wants
you to come down.
Should we wait?
No, she'll be okay.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah. She's nuts.
This hurts me
more than it hurts you.
We wanted you
to be one of us,
to share the luck
of living in this building.
We even threw you a party.
And how do you thank us?
Laughing at us,
and what's worse, trying
to run off, playing dirty.
Domínguez died
because you double-crossed him!
What was the deal?
"50-50 and fuck the rest
of those cocksuckers"?
Domínguez didn't
deserve to end up like that!
God! Do you know how many
years I've been
behind this project,
getting these people together?
I've turned down jobs,
well-paying jobs,
just to stay here.
I knew things would
fall apart without me.
You see what happens?
A treat for the kids.
My first vacation in 20 years,
and you appear
and fuck everything up!
Who do you think you are?
I'll tell you.
You're a lying whore who
hasn't a penny!
This isn't even your flat!
But that doesn't matter.
I feel sorry for your kind.
What are you saying?
Don't play dumb.
You understand me.
You people think
only of yourselves.
You probably
don't have a family, either.
You people don't
want responsibilities.
You just want
to live in the present.
Fuck everyone else.
Well, we're different here.
This is a community.
García's hip is bad
and he eats lunch
at his daughter's house.
He needs a little car
to get around town.
Paquita, on the 5th floor,
is 40 years old and still single.
Know why?
Her mouth is
disgusting and
she's never been kissed.
She needs to get
her teeth fixed.
It's all here on this list,
corrected year after year.
Know what I'm talking about?
About solidarity, respect.
We believe
in respecting others.
You don't know
what that means.
Just finish it!
Don't tell me what to do.
You killed the engineer,
didn't you?
He didn't want to guard
the old man. Just two hours a day.
No, he was above all that.
He didn't have
a family to support.
Out living it up to all hours.
Drunks coming in and leaving.
He kept us all awake.
He was destroying
the community.
So kill me, too and stop boring me
with your sermons.
You're a fraud and a thief,
like me, like everybody.
No, I'm not a thief.
I'm not a thief.
I have a right to it, I do.
We did the sports lottery
together.
I helped him
guess the scores.
He asked me for advice.
He said...
"Sporting against Real Sociedad"...
And I...
I...
I said...
"Tie".
I don't know, itjust
came out of my mouth.
No one else in Spain
marked "Tie". Just me.
I said, "Tie".
When I heard he'd
won the jackpot,
I was glad.
I swear I was glad.
And he didn't want to share.
As if we didn't exist.
We were neighbors.
A lifetime together, meeting
in the elevator, in the bar...
It meant nothing to him.
He could have given us part,
orjust gifts.
But no, he wanted it
all for himself,
the Goddamn greedy fucker.
I've dreamt about
this moment ever since.
If I hadn't spoken,
if I'd shut my mouth,
if I hadn't said "Tie"...
the bastard wouldn't
have ruined our lives.
Are you going
to keep it all?
What?
You wouldn't kill
for 30 million,
but you would
for 300 million.
People kill for 15,000 pesetas.
You needed the neighbors.
You couldn't guard the old man
by yourself. You planned this.
- That's a lie.
- Now you don't need them.
But how will you get out?
Will you kill them all?
You'll need an excuse
to take out the suitcase.
You must have one.
You've had 20 years
to think about it.
And about getting rid
of your beloved wife and kids.
I love my wife as much
as the first day we met.
She must be a good woman
to have gone
without vacations.
But with money, you can
get something better.
Shut up.
Someone who doesn't know,
who matches
your new house and pool,
your new convertible.
Have you thought about it?
Get in the bathtub, I don't
want bloodstains on the floor.
Get in the bathtub, I said!
100, 200, 300, 400, 500...
What are you doing?
Why did you buy that?
Don't distract me,
I'll have to start over.
I'm worried about you.
Are you okay?
Yes, Mom. Leave me alone.
Well, whatever happens,
don't leave the flat.
Everything will
turn out all right.
Hello? Yes, speaking.
Who's this?
What agency?
The real estate agency.
Yes, what is it?
Look, I can't talk
to you right now.
What?
Who told you?
A neighbor.
Yes, I am living here
and I suppose I'm fired.
Don't worry, in an hour
I'll have it clean.
No, give me 90 minutes.
What? Someone else
is coming to see it?
Is this the only flat
in Madrid?
Hello?
There's no one here,
come in.
Well, this is a great flat.
Here are the super-advantages.
One, near the subway.
Two, downtown.
Three, schools for the kids,
and four, parks
where they can play.
We can see the kitchen,
if you want.
- Does it have a garage?
- No, it doesn't.
If it did, it'd have
been sold by now.
Hi, I'm Julia García,
from the agency.
What's going on?
They must be friends of hers.
It's plastic,
I can't hear anything.
Excuse me.
I'd like a minute
- alone with you.
- Of course.
- What's your name?
- Javier Pacheco.
We have to tell Castro.
He said to tell people
he's in the bar.
Great. I'll go get him.
But he's not there. He just
doesn't want his wife to know.
About what?
His affair with blonde.
From the videoclub?
You didn't know? Haven't
you noticed he's always
carrying videos?
Lately he's seen more movies
than Woody Allen.
Impossible.
She's hot. I got a card and
I don't even have a VCR.
What do I care about
that loser's private life?
Well, since you asked...
- You slapped me!
- You deserved that and more.
You see a couple of tits
and that's that.
You all have shit for brains.
Listen, Jaime or Javi.
I need a favor.
I rang three times.
They said they'd call.
You did very well,
Jaime or Javi.
Just don't show them
the bedroom.
What do I tell them?
The truth.
There's a bad leak.
- Is that the reason?
- No, silly.
Let's say I wasn't
alone yesterday
and I'm not today, either.
Did he do that?
Love can be very strange.
But you're still so young.
See, there is a leak.
Yes, it's not worth
showing them.
You're new and don't know,
but this is normaI in our work.
The bosses know.
It's a kind of fringe benefit.
Still, I think I'll wait
a few months before...
I bring girls to the flats.
You have
to find the girl first.
So today for you,
tomorrow for me.
LUCK HITS
SAN JERONIMO STREET
Julia!
Something's wrong
with my head.
Help me.
Julia, what have you done?
Come here!
Julia, come here!
Julia,
it's Oswaldo. Open up.
No, Oswaldo, I'm sorry.
Where's Emilio?
Did he hurt you?
They're waiting for him.
Who sent you this time?
Castro? Ramona?
No, forget them. I'm alone.
This is our chance
to get away. Hurry.
- They'll come back.
- You just want the suitcase.
Yes, I want the money.
But to share with you.
They've all gone crazy.
- I'm afraid.
- Julia!
Help me!
The airport's an hour away.
Tomorrow we'll be
far from here.
Together?
Why not?
There's something between us
and you know it. We need
each other. We're like
castaways.
Two castaways on an island.
An island full of monsters.
Don't cry, honey,
I won't let them hurt you.
Open the door, my love.
I need you
more than anything.
Julia! My car's parked
downstairs. Open up.
Can't you hear me, darling?
No, no, no!
Holy shit! The bitch!
- Come on!
- My God!
It can't be true!
My God, it can't be true!
Help!
They want to kill me!
Hey! Didn't you hear me?
Help!
Hey, what's up?
How are things?
Hey! Hey!
Mommy! Mommy!
Get moving, damnit!
You wanted to escape too,
crazy old man?
Come here!
The door's blocked.
Push! Push! Goddamnit!
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be
- Thy name...
- Up here! Hurry!
- Julia!
- Charli?
Yes.
Come up.
Come on, come on!
- Where's the suitcase?
- No, forget the money.
There's no time!
- They're already here!
- The suitcase!
Where are we going?
He was my friend.
We were going to escape.
So you know how to get out?
He had to die just now.
It isn't fair.
Run!
The bitch!
She's on the roof!
Come on!
Fucking bitches!
Do they have to push me?
They'll take the suitcase!
That way!
This is my plan.
I'll create a distraction,
like in the Death Star.
What star?
Han Solo distracted
the Stormtroopers while
Luke and the Princess fled,
remember?
This isn't "Star Wars".
The Force is with me.
They could kill you!
Don't worry,
nothing will happen.
I'll play dumb like always.
Trust me.
Too late.
The Princess has fled.
The Rebellion will triumph.
Hooray for the Republic!
Republic?
What fucking republic?
Why is this retard here?
Stop it! You'll kill him!
- Keep him here!
- Come on, Castro.
I'll see you later.
I told you to stay home.
She said
she would marry me.
Your father was right.
We should have
drowned you at birth.
That suitcase is mine.
My God!
Give it to me.
You're going to fall!
Let me go and it's yours!
I won't say anything,
I swear.
Give it to me!
Shoot, Ramona!
Shoot again, stupid!
She's getting away!
Stupid? Me?
- You don't know me.
- Just shoot, damnit!
Not my Cookie! Not my Cookie!
Not my Cookie!
What are you doing, Ramona?
Stay calm!
- You go that way!
- We're together in this!
Yes, yes, yes...
What are you doing?
I'm going after you, honey.
Don't run, honey!
You're getting out of here,
but feet first!
Give it to me right now!
- You wanted to cut in line.
- Let go!
You wanted it
all for yourself!
You pig!
What did you do to Emilio?
What?
You want to keep the suitcase.
How does that feel?
Give me the suitcase.
You won't need it.
You hypocrite!
You hold that suitcase
like your soul
was inside!
You're just like us,
like everyone!
No, I won't be like you!
You can't help it.
You were born that way,
it's in your blood!
You ran over everyone.
Say you're like me!
Say it!
No, Ramona.
You'd never do this!
NEIGHBORS KILL EACH OTHER
FOR MONEY THAT DOESN'T EXIST
JEDI KNIGHT NEEDS PRINCESS
FOR RELATIONSHIP
MEET ME AT
"THE BEAR AND THE MADROŇO TREE"
THE BEAR AND THE MADROŇO TREE
I spent three days at the bear
statue before I heard about the bar.
Why didn't you tell me
about the suitcase?
They'd have noticed and
you wouldn't have escaped.
Only that?
I also wanted to see
if you were like my mom.
Want some consommé?
- With sherry.
- Another one, please.
What was in
the other suitcase?
You're something else!
You don't deserve it.
Fucking great, Charli!
- Shall we dance?
- Okay.
PortugaI,
why do I love you so?
Portugal, why do you
seem so happy?